Elavarasi Chinnappa

.Net Developer



Senior Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience in overseeing all aspects of the Software Development Life Cycle. Proficient in Software Development using C#, .NET Core, Sitecore, Azure, Database Management and Agile/Scrum methodology. Certified .NET Developer involved in developing web applications and Microservices.

Skills

Tech Stack:

C#, .NET Core, ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, REST API, ADO.NET, WSDL, Entity Framework, Webform, Web Services, WCF, LINQ, NUnit, Javascript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Okta, Azure & Sitecore.

Data Engineering:

MS SQL Server, Mongo DB for Sitecore analytics

Others:

Git/GitHub, TFS, JIRA, Agile Scrum

Certifications

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900)

December 2019

Sitecore® **9.0 Certified Platform Associate Developer** *August 2019*

Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Application (70-486)April 2017

Sitecore® **XP 8 Website Development** July 2016

Education

Bachelor Of Technology (Information Technology)

Anna University, Chennai, India July 2008 - Mar 2012

Accomplishments

- 2 Times Best performer Hats Off Award in Mindtree
- 4 Times spot on A Team Award in Mindtree
- 4 Times Gracias Award in Mindtree
- 2 Times sparkling Team member Award in Accenture
- Extra Mile Award in Virtusa.

elavarasi.chinnappa184@gmail.com

+353 899516696

Dublin, Ireland

https://www.linkedin.com/in/elavarasichinnappa-0bb74918

https://elavarasi-chinnappa.github.io/

Work Experience

Mindtree Pvt Ltd Module Lead

Sydney/Chennai Jan 2021 - May 2023

- Designed and developed microservices applications using .NET Core and MS SQL Server in Agile methodology.
- Implemented Single Sign-On (SSO) authentication and authorization using Okta, enhancing security and user experience.
- Led DevOps initiatives by configuring Azure CI/CD pipelines, automating deployment processes, and ensuring smooth integration of .NET Core and React code.
- Achieved a 50% improvement in application performance through the implementation of Redis Cache and code optimization.

Accenture Senior Analyst

Chennai, India Nov 2017 - Jan 2021

- Developed web applications using C#, ASP .NET MVC5, Javascript, JQuery and Sitecore (CMS) 10.2.
- Achieved more than 75% code coverage through comprehensive unit testing using N-Unit, enhancing code quality and reliability.
- Managed a team of 8 members, facilitating user story analysis, estimation, technical guidance, and Implementing Tech Debt.

Virtusa Consultancy Services Pvt Ltd Associate Consultant

Chennai, India Aug 2015 - Nov 2017

- Involved in transitioning legacy application to Sitecore XP 8.0 ASP .NET, MS SQL, Javascript and JQuery resulting in enhanced performance and modernized user experience.
- Streamlined CRM systems by reducing the number of platforms used, leading to increased operational efficiency and reduced maintenance overhead.

Tata Consultancy Services Pvt Ltd System Engineer

Chennai, India Nov 2012 - July 2015

- Contributed to the application development process by employing Test-Driven Development (TDD) framework, ensuring robust and reliable software.
- Integrated the application by consuming WCF and Web API services, enhancing the application's functionality and data exchange capabilities.